Part 6.2 video ad frameworks.
This is probably one of the most important parts of the course,
because this is gonna teach you how to set up ads or creative
content in a very formulaic way.
Video ad frameworks create a dependable sequence. Uh,
create a dependable sequence structure to follow. Okay?
Especially if you don't have a script in place.
Having these video out frameworks in your mind, or you know, all written down,
it's gonna allow you to put things together a lot faster.
You're gonna be able to see clearly what the next step is in the,
the editing process, or video creation process or scripting process.
That way you can actually, um, recreate your success over and over again.
This is the ADA framework. It stands for attention, interest,
desire, and action. This is a, this, I didn't coin this term, um,
but it's a very useful acronym to understand how
video ads work or any type of, I would say, um,
video on social media works,
at least one that's trying to drive some sort of result is within the first
three seconds, you must grab their attention, right?
Content must stop the prospect. It says here,
three second video views divided by impressions equals the percentage of people
that engage. 25 to 30% is a solid benchmark.
So you can measure this stuff on the backend, wherever, on Facebook, TikTok,
wherever the case may be, where wherever your advertising,
but you wanna be hitting a 25 to 30% stop rate,
which means they are stopping to watch your video.
So this is where that scroll stopper comes in, and it,
and this is where it matters the most,
and I think this is one of the key things that people do the least of. Um,
so focusing on that first three seconds is absolutely key,
and everybody will say it. Who's been in the game for a while.
Number two comes down to the interest section.
So once you've got their attention, you have to keep their interest, right?
So content must hold the prospect video,
average watch times above three seconds on Facebook and Instagram,
or above 30 seconds on YouTube, right? Depending on where you're,
where you're actually advertising, you've gotta keep their attention.
If you're not keeping their attention, they're gonna drop off. So you got their,
you know, you got their attention. Now you gotta keep their interest. I mean,
if you're not keeping them interested, they're gonna bounce, right?
So every single second is super, super valuable on,
on social media and on when you're making ads, because you're essentially,
once that person's gone, they're gone.
So there's various ways to keep their interest.
And whether you're an editor, um, or whoever, or, or,
or shooting video, you know,
keeping it engaging every single second is like changing the screen or zooming
in, or zooming out, or adding the emoji grid. Adding a caption,
like you can see some of the pros who who've mastered this,
they sustain the attention and the interest all throughout the entire video.
So, number three,
D for desire content must make the prospect explore further.
So this is where your C T R comes in, which means click-through rate,
and average outbound click-through rates above 1% means the ad.
Um, what's compelling, okay? So this is a very important metric.
If you've never run any ads,
your C T R just basically means if they've clicked through on the ad, okay?
And the higher, uh,
your click through rate is the more effective your ad means.
So it means that whatever you are putting out there was more relevant to them
and they're interested in clicking through. So, you know,
I think this is the one of the biggest metrics to follow,
especially if you know you're making content. It's like, okay,
are people actually interested in clicking?
Did they even make it through the video?
They make it for through the first thir, uh, three seconds. Um,
those are all strong indicators, uh, or, or key indicators for you to follow.
So there's different ways to, to make, uh,
a video more clickable, and we can talk about that later on. And lastly,
you have a, for action content must be effectively set up, uh,
must effectively set up the final desired result,
the bottom of the creative funnel, cost per purchase. And purchases themselves,
obviously you have your roas. So if they actually decide to take action,
if they actually decide to buy whatever it is you are putting out there,
whatever your product you're selling is,
we'll determine what your return on ad spend is, right?
So you've got their attention, you've gotta keep their interest,
you've gotta get them to click, and then you've gotta get them to buy.
Those are the, uh, the four steps in the ADA framework.
And so everything kind of combines into that framework when, um,
you structure out your video ads. So let's just jump right into that.
Here is the ADA framework in a timeline sequence. And when I say timeline,
I mean your video editing sequence, because as a video editor,
we look at everything horizontally, right from left to right.
And when you're able to look at things from left to right,
it's a lot easier to visualize what's the next logical step.
So for me, attention means your hooks, your scroll stoppers.
This is that first three seconds that you need to be really focusing on.
Keep getting their attention, right?
And we'll break into what are these potential hooks, emotional hooks,
sensory hooks, intellectual hooks. We have a description of what those are.
After those first three seconds, then we want to keep them interested.
So we gotta keep them curious and engaged. And there's few ways to do that.
You know, you don't want to bore them. You want to keep them on their toes,
you want to keep them super excited or intrigued within that, you know,
the four second mark, four to 10 seconds.
And then once you've established their interest,
now you've gotta create desire in that desire framework or that sequence.
You can include product, introductions, demonstrations, benefits, features,
resolution, social proof, authority, case studies,
whatever the case may be for your video ad.
And depending on how long you want the video to be,
this is where you plug in all of those, uh,
USPS and benefits and features and whatnot,
so that they feel compelled to actually click through. And then lastly,
you have your call to action,
which is typically at the end of the video where you include your offer,
your call to action, your graphic, your logo.
You can even include scarcity or urgency here.
And this is basically the four step process to creating viral videos
or highly engaging, uh, video ads.
And so let's see what this looks like in an actual video format.
Okay? So this is a video ad that I've, uh,
I edited for a client that has done very, very well,
and I've iterated on this ad many, many times. Um,
so the hook right here, it was a, uh,
a woman basically cussing. She was tasting the drink. The,
the product is called Three Spirit. It's a non-alcoholic beverage.
So when she drinks it for the first time, she actually cusses out loud.
She says, oh f**k, oh s**t, I forget.
But I bleeped out the word and then I put an emoji over
her mouth, um, and I actually zoomed into her face.
So I did a lot of little,
I would say like editing tricks to try to keep her attention,
keep the attention to not just make it a basic, uh, reaction.
I added more layers to it. Um, and then the second hook, I actually added,
uh, a caption here, how to get a buzz without the hangover.
And this headline actually performed best.
'cause there's a curiosity aspect to that, right? You want to know what it is.
So when you combine those two together, how to get a buzz without a hangover,
number one, that's a curiosity factor. Like what could that be? And number two,
you have the visual of her, you know, it, it's kind of a crazy, she, you know,
she's got crazy hair, a crazy backdrop, um, crazy colors going on.
And then number three, you have an audio hook, which her is her talking,
um, plus cussing. So it's like all of your senses are being tickled. Um,
and then moving into the interest format. I haven't really,
I haven't really, uh, explained what the actual product is yet, but I just say,
the internet is going crazy for these magical mocktails, okay?
Haven't revealed anything yet.
So the viewer is still on their toes. You know, if I went from,
you know, how to get a buzzer that the hangover introducing this product,
you know, it could bore people because it's like, oh, that's what it is.
But if you build up the, the suspense, you build up that tension, uh,
it it, they're more likely to, to keep watching. So, for example, another, uh,
when I watch like TikTok videos or something, keep watching till the end,
you know, here are five tips to get X, Y, and Z. And then, you know, you're,
you're almost forced to watch the rest of the video because you want the payoff
at the end. So in the desire portion,
this is where the product's introduced, where we have, uh,
key benefits as well as testimonials. Uh, there's a lot going on in,
in this section right here. This is probably a bulk of the video,
but I didn't include all the screenshots just because, you know,
it would take too much space.
But this is where we're actually selling the product.
We're creating the desire to actually take action and click through. So,
uh, people are probably clicking through within this portion right here,
because they're seeing a lot of social proof,
they're seeing why it's good for them, et cetera, et cetera. And then lastly,
if they made it all the way to the end of the video,
we've got a nice little call to action,
a branded photo with a C t A and an arrow. Okay?
So that's the main format right here. And I'll link the video down below,
and we'll also do a breakdown of this video in another, in another video,
another tutorial. But this is a,
a common framework that I use over and over again, uh,
to create very, very effective video ads.
Another thing too is you can apply this framework to any video ad style as well
as any length. So if you wanted to shorten the video ad,
you can reduce the amount of benefits and features that you're gonna be talking
about in a video. Um, if you wanna lengthen it, just add more selling points.
Really, it, it just comes down to how your audience responds to,
you know, the video and which platform you're working on. So if it's YouTube,
it's going to, you know, you could, you could get away with a longer video,
but if it's TikTok, it's gonna be really quick. Or Facebook, you know,
somewhere in the middle. Remember,
hooks will always remain three to eight seconds of the video.
The other segments can vary in length. I just want to preface, you know,
our attention ability to capture attention is really the key to any success
on social media or any type of video creative or any type of written posts.
At the end of the day, we have a million things going on,
and if we don't capture their attention, you're done. Right?
So this is non-negotiable. You cannot change the length of this.
You could even shorten it, to be honest. Have a,
a two second hook versus a a five second hook.
And it could be as simple as like flashing like an image of somebody,
or like a graphic thumbnail, and then cutting to the video.
These are all different various techniques, but remember, this is the key,
and you wanna make sure that this is the thing you're testing most often.
So as we moved move forward into understanding all these different pieces,
uh, I want you to think of your video sequences and clips in modular pieces.
Okay? So modular meaning like individual, think of like a Lego piece.
When you have modular pieces, you are able to move them around, okay?
And when you know this, and when you have this, editing becomes much simpler.
All right? So let's show you an example here.
So this is an example of modular video assets.
I like to think of it as buckets. So if I, I have, I have kids,
so we put all of their toys in different buckets.
So we have their action figures, we have their Legos, we have, uh,
their car toys, we have their wooden toys, we have puzzles.
And so the list goes on and on, right? And the same thing, uh, uh,
the same thing is applicable to your video assets or all of your creative
assets. Uh, and in this case, we have our hooks, our animations,
our lifestyle footage, our pain points, our product features, our B-roll,
our authorities, you know, these could be like interviews or doctors.
We can have demonstrations, social proof, CTAs, U G C images,
product image list goes on and on.
But I would say majority can fit into these categories because this is the most
common categories that we use within our, our production.
So this is very important as an editor, as you organize all your footage,
because if you know where all of your stuff is at,
then you can actually utilize it a lot more effectively. Okay?
So it's almost like, Hey, I only need this tool. I only need this screw.
I only need that one, right? Versus having, it's like a toolbox.
If you have all of your screws just fly, like,
just laid out on the table as a complete mess, it's gonna be very,
very difficult to sort and filter which ones you actually need, uh,
versus which ones are not gonna be useful.
And that's the exact same thing when it comes to, to your video assets.
And as an editor, it's so important that you know where all of your stuff is at,
and you have to know which, like, which assets are gonna be most effective,
and you have to study this stuff. And if you don't,
then you're just gonna use the wrong stuff. That could be,
that could be thrown away,
or you're not using the right stuff that could actually make the video take off.
So here's what I mean by modularity, modular format,
uh, and applying the ADA format to it. Okay?
So as an attention grabber or a hook or a scroll stopper,
there's so many different names for it,
you can include a pain point shot in here. You know, if, if,
let's say the three spirit one, if, um, you know,
someone was drinking booze or alcohol and they're spitting it out,
that would be a pain point, right? Um, and then to gain their interest,
we can include an animation. Well, you know, this,
this weird new alcoholic, non-alcoholic beverage, uh, has shown to,
um, reduce hangovers, you know, or, or completely eliminate hangovers.
And you can show like maybe like an animation of,
of like it going into your liver and it being processed, whatever.
I'm just talking out loud here. Um, and then when the, when that's over,
'cause you still haven't really revealed it,
then you can show demonstrations of the product as well as social proof to get
them excited and just want to click on the video. And then lastly,
you have the C t A, right? So that's one variation.
So you have all these tools, it's like, okay,
well how can I reformat this video, uh, in a different way?
Here's a different way. Okay, let's do the same thing,
but let's swap out the animation for authority. All right?
So what I mean by that is, okay, we have the same pain point of, okay,
the person drinking and throwing up, and then next we include, let's say,
a doctor who talks about the toxicity of, of,
of alcohol and why that's so bad for you, right?
You haven't revealed the product yet, but you're just saying, Hey, like if,
if you, if you've ever done this before and you don't want these consequences,
we have a solution for you.
So that is another opportunity to test something out.
And that's actually something we might be able to propose to the team, um,
because this is a very crucial time in the sequence, right?
We're looking at the three to ten second, or three to eight second mark here,
where you still have their attention, you know, you're keeping them interested.
Um, and so, yeah, that, that's something we, we might even test
later on in the video. If, let's say, you know,
that this pain point and this authority piece works very well,
then maybe you can start playing with further down in the video. Um,
if you look at some of your metrics and see that there's a drop off rate,
you know, within the, let's say, I don't know, 20, 25 second mark,
um, you guys, as an editor, you should go back to your timeline and be like,
okay,
what's happening in the 25 second mark where I can make this more engaging? Um,
if people are dropping off there,
then they're either getting bored or they don't really care,
or it's not appealing to them. So why don't we spice it up?
Why don't we add something? Instead of social proof,
let's add another pain point. Let's, uh, twist the knife a little bit. Get them,
uh, re-engaged in the video.
Here's a little demonstration or a little illustration of what I mean by putting
all of your, uh, video assets into buckets or labeling them.
Just like Legos,
we are able to sort and filter our own footage from hook, intro,
benefit features, social proof animations, pain points, call to action,
you name it. If you don't name it, if you don't have a name for something,
then it's just gonna be floating without a category and you're not gonna know
when to use it. And I think this is so important,
this is something that I've learned over the years, is like,
you've got to know where all your assets at. You've got to label everything,
and you've got to be super organized. Uh, these are your tools, man. You're,
as an editor, your job is to be able to maximize the resources that you have.
And sometimes you don't have the best resources.
So you have to know what's in your toolbox in order to create something worthy.
Here's another example of doing the, the ADA format within the timeline.
So you got your hook, your intro, your benefit, your feature,
your call to action, right? This is a very simple simplified format,
or a simplified timeline,
but this just gives you a perspective of what that looks like on the timeline.
So you can go to the extent of even creating some of these guides for you within
Premier, um, so that you, you're aware of where, where you're at in the video.
So it's like, okay, right now I'm, I'm focusing on the intro.
So let me carve out three seconds for the intro there.
Here are some additional video ad frameworks that could be useful to test. Um,
here you have demonstration benefit and validation.
It's a simple three step process. There's no call to action there.
Here you're just showing the problem, showing the solution, um,
how it benefits the user, and then maybe some social proof, like, boom,
you're done. This is like a 15 second ad right here. Next you have hook,
demonstration benefit, explain the product and then call to action.
This could be a little bit of a longer video, but this framework,
uh, could be used more of like a, a cold traffic ad as well. Um, it,
it really depends. It really depends,
depends on what you have as assets that you can create these
frameworks under. So if you have a lot of content, you know,
feel free to to chop it up, uh, and, and create something engaging. 'cause um,
even brands don't realize their own potential for their own content because no
one is looking at it that way. And this is what makes you an advanced editor,
is being able to assess the content that a brand or a company has sent
you,
be able to organize it and then create a framework and a
converting a high converting ad out of it. Uh, because that's,
that's literally what people pay you lots of money for 'cause they don't know
how to do it themselves. And this is exactly how you do it yourself. Last one,
you've got a benefit. Explain c t a, show the benefit to the user,
explain how it works. C t a, right? So really depends on the format.
If we wanna go shorter, if we wanna go longer or middle range, um, like I said,
these could be rearranged,
but your hook is gonna stay there and your C T A is gonna stay there.
But there are some exceptions.
If you wanted to add a c t A in between the video,
that's actually a thing I've been seeing a lot of people test.
You can put CTAs like after the first, you know,
five or so seconds or the first 10 seconds just because people will drop off and
you want to get them to click. So lots of crazy ways,
lots of cool ways that you can do stuff these days.